<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ModInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <displayName>Reduced Range</displayName>
  <description>Reduced Attack Range for all Ranged Units

* All Ranged Mounted Units and all Ranged Barbarian Units have a Range of 1 (originally 2)
 (no change to Slingers, Range stays at 2)
* Infantry Archers have a Range of 2 (originally 3)
* Onagers and Mangonels have a Range of 2-3 (originally 2-4, 2-5)
* all nations start with Warriors (no more Slingers at the start).
* Polearm Units Spearman, Pikeman, Conscript, and the UUs Hoplite and Phalangite get Cleave (instead of Pierce)
* Gaesata and Geja Archer no longer have Pierce (originally 1 Tile at 25%)
* Crossbowman, Polybolos and Elite Gaesata only attack Pierce at 25% (down from 50%)
* Ballista Pierce attack only reaches 1 Tile behind target (instead of 2)
* Towers provide no Range increase (originally +1)
 (no change to Hills Terrain and Marksman Promotion, they still increase Range by 1)
* Spearman recieves +10% Defense from Tech Forestry and +20% Defense from Tech Manor.
* Pikeman's +100% against Mounted Units is reduced to +50% (originally +100%).
* Cataphract Strength reduced to 8 ! and Circle is removed, Training Cost reduced to 120 (originally 160)
* Tech requirements for Pikeman and Cataphract adjusted: 
 - Pikeman Tech Infantry Square now only costs 1000 Science but requires Manor too, not just Battle Line,
 - Cataphract Tech Barding now requires Steel instead of Battle Line (in addition to Martial Code, which remains).


Reduced Range makes movement more important, making the mobile Mounted Units even stronger, 
which is why Spearman gets a buff (which was needed anyway, imo). And with Units in battle
being closer together, routing is stronger, so the Cataphract gets a nerf to 8 Strength.
Because the Cataphract has only 8 Strength now, the Pikeman no longer needs to have +100%
against Mounted Units, and get's the same +50% as the other Polearm Units, making it equal
to the Phalangite.

You can contact me on discord, and only there. 
If you try any other way to contact me, my answer could take months.</description>
  <modpicture>ReducedRange.jpg</modpicture>
  <author>Fimbulvetr</author>
  <modplatform>Modio</modplatform>
  <modioID>2244402</modioID>
  <modioFileID>0</modioFileID>
  <modversion>0.3.7.1</modversion>
  <modbuild>1.0.73676</modbuild>
  <homepage>https://forums.civfanatics.com/threads/mod-fims-collection-of-small-mods.678240/</homepage>
  <tags>GameInfo</tags>
  <singlePlayer>true</singlePlayer>
  <multiplayer>true</multiplayer>
  <scenario>false</scenario>
  <scenarioToggle>false</scenarioToggle>
  <blocksMods>false</blocksMods>
  <modDependencies />
  <modIncompatibilities />
  <modWhitelist />
  <gameContentRequired>NONE</gameContentRequired>
</ModInfo>