<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ModInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <displayName>Little Family Balance Tweak</displayName>
  <description>Many changes were made to Families lately. Some of these changes were reverted, other changes applied.

Some features require Better AI Base DLL mod functionality

Clerics: no longer gain access to the Project to found a Religion,
  the free tier 4 Tech Bonus (Monasticism) was also removed. 
 Instead they get a Court Soldier, and in their Seat they can rush Projects with Citizens.
  The -50% training time for Disciples applies to all their cities, not just the Seat.
  All Cities get +2 Happiness (instead of +1 (1.0.65965)
 (Better AI feature) Clerics unlock in their own Cities:
 -- State Religion's Monasteries with Divination Tech
 -- State Religion's Temples with Metaphysics Tech and Strong Culture in the City

Traders: 5 Bonuses were removed:
  -10 turns for Hamlet Class Upgrades,
  Road building without cooldown for Family Workers,
  free Fair in Seat, 
  +5 Money from Specialists (1.0.65965 added +2 Culture, 1.0.66355 changed it to Money),
  +100% to Nets.
 They were replaced with: 
  5 Orders can be stored for the next turn (tied to the free Early Market (+15% Money, no Specialist) Improvement in seat), 
  +400 Money when Founding a City, 
  +2 Culture from Luxuries sent to City
  +2 Culture from Precious Resources (1.0.65965 removed this)
 (Better AI feature) Traders unlock in their own Cities:
 -- Harbor with Navigation Tech and Developing Culture in the City
 -- Market with Polis Tech and Developing Culture in the City
 -- Grocer with Navigation Tech and Strong Culture in the City
 -- Ferry Unit (immediately at game start)
 
Patrons keep their +2 Culture from Specialists (1.0.65965 removed this), and don't get +25% Culture from Bullion Resources (1.0.71795 added this)
 and their Cities only gain +1 Happiness Level on Culture Level upgrade (1.0.71795 changed this to +2)
Statemen keep they Treasury I City founding bonus (1.0.66355 remved this), and don't get -25% Upfront Cost reduction for Specialists (1.0.66355 added this)
Riders' import Projects don't add the Resource to the map, just enable building the respective Units,
 and those Projects have Tech requirements: Husbandry for Import Horse, Land Consolidation for Import Elephant and Import Camel.
  (In 1.0.70671 Riders' Seat spawned Horses, Elephants and Camels while removing the ability of the Seat to build the specific Units without the Resource,
   and 1.0.70751 removed that and replaced it with Player-unique projects that add the Resources on the map.)
Artisans keep their Ingenuity for Siege Units, only for Ships this is replaced with -25% Resource Cost (In 1.0.71309 Ingenuity was replaced for both Unit types)
 
Sages: no longer gains a random Tech, gain Archive only in Seat, instead they keep their -20% Upfront Cost for Urban Specialists.

You can contact me on discord, and only there. 
If you try any other way to contact me, my answer could take months.</description>
  <modpicture>FamilyBalance.png</modpicture>
  <author>Fimbulvetr</author>
  <modplatform>Modio</modplatform>
  <modioID>2226892</modioID>
  <modioFileID>0</modioFileID>
  <modversion>0.6.11</modversion>
  <modbuild>1.0.73676</modbuild>
  <homepage>https://forums.civfanatics.com/threads/mod-fims-collection-of-small-mods.678240/</homepage>
  <tags>Family,GameInfo</tags>
  <singlePlayer>true</singlePlayer>
  <multiplayer>true</multiplayer>
  <scenario>false</scenario>
  <scenarioToggle>false</scenarioToggle>
  <blocksMods>false</blocksMods>
  <modDependencies>
    <string>Boat</string>
  </modDependencies>
  <modIncompatibilities />
  <modWhitelist />
  <gameContentRequired>NONE</gameContentRequired>
</ModInfo>