<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ModInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <displayName>FimMod</displayName>
  <description>  A collection of small changes that didn't get their own separate mod.
  requires Base DLL Mod

- Event "Influence of Money": The character asking to be bribed can't be honorable.
- Adopting removes "Bastard" trait.
- Info text is no longer ambiguous if it's about the Improvement Class or its lvl 1 Improvement (Hamlet, Odeon, Market, Library, Courthouse, Garrison)
- Capitals get free Walls to make early rushing less viable, especially with low AI Development settings.
- Special Unit abilities replacement: 2 Defense-oriented abilities were replaced with normal Defense boni.
   Tactician (Melee Counter): +50% Defense vs. Melee (originally: does full Attack Damage when Defending against Melee)
   (Critial Immune): +10% Defense (originally: Unit is immune to the extra Damage from Critial Strikes)
- Schemer Leaders get flat +4 Orders now (originally: +1 Orders per War and the ability to sell 2 Legitimacy for 10 Orders every turn)
- River bridging is unlocked by Polis Tech (originally: unlocked by enacting Engineering Law)
- Improvement lists for selected Worker show as a grid of icons for all filters, not just "All". 
- Wonder nerf:
  Pyramids -25% adopt Law Cost (from -50%),
  Apadanda -50% maint. reduction only to city (instead of all cities),
  Ishtar Gate only +50 culture (from +100)
  Cothon no longer produces Triremes, instead gives a -25% Train time reducting,
  Colosseum doesn't produce Swordsmen and doesn't give +1 Training in City,
    instead all new Infantry Units in the City start with Tough, and all Cities get flat +1 Training;
  Heliopolis gives only +0.5 Order per Acolyte, instead of +1 per Shrine;
  Al Khazneh now gives +20% Money and upgrades all Treasury I to Treasury II where possible and adds Treasury I 
   to Cities that don't have it, no longer gives Luxuries;.
- (Base DLL feature) some lvl 1 and a few lvl 2 improvements can now be unlocked earlier, in addition to their normal unlock Tech + Culture.
   (Example: A City with Strong Culture can build a Courthouse at Tech Phalanx already, one Tech earlier.)
   Ministry no longer needs to be right next to the Courthouse.
- (Base DLL feature) Baths are stronger now, but every city can only have 1 Bath now. Which one, that is decided by City Biome: 
   Cold Baths in Arid/Dessert, Hot Baths in Tundra, Warm Baths in Temperate regions. Biome is calculated from non-Urban Land Tiles in City territory.
- (Base DLL feature) Embarking costs 1 Movement point, like crossing a river.
- (Base DLL feature) Amphibious Units can cross Rivers, and Embark, without extra Movement costs. 
- (Base DLL feature) Roads without Bridges inside your Territory reduce River Crossing extra cost by 1/3 Movement point.
- (Base DLL feature) Hurrying: cost calculation factors in normal turn production, no overflow afterwards. Also, only 1x hurrying per turn.
- Clergy Trait (Courtier Trait, not to be confused with the new type of Characters with the same name) is now part of Religious Trait group; 
  removed Insane from Weak Trait group
- Centralization Law keeps its +10 civics/turn
- disabled Forts
- Discontent reduction reverted, Citizens give no negative family opinion, Growth still gets reduced by Discontent (64759)
- Roads no longer cost Stone, and with a Builder Leader a Worker can build multiple Roads per Turn
- (Base DLL feature) Agent Networks Setup Cost is now: 200 + (50 * Number of Networks) + (100 * City Culture Level) (from: 200 + (100 * Number of Networks))
- Ask to Declare War Mission is disabled. It's too strong, too cheap and doesn't come with enough limitations. It's just an exploit.
- Fortify is now +10% Defense, 3 Turns max (from +5%, 5 Turns), Testudo is +25% Defense against Ranged, 2 Turns max (from +20%, 3 Turns max)
- Wanton and Rightous Trait don't replace each other
- (Base DLL feature) Enlisted Units don't get assigned to any Family.
- AI Players recieve 33% more "fake" Events to better compensate for the fact that they don't get normal Events like human Players.
- (Base DLL feature) Added Discontent Level 0
- No more Techs from Ruins
- for Competitive games, most Events that can give a free Tech are disabled,
- for Competitive games, all Events that can give a free Settler are disabled,
- for Competitive games, one more Event that can give is Tribal Alliance is disabled (Look upon my Armies and Despair),
- most AI Leader Traits now affect their Diplomatic behavior, not just their Archetypes
- all Events that were limited to at least Difficulty The Strong and up can now trigger as low as Difficulty The Good.
- The Event that ends Exploration and founds a Religion was removed (too easy to get for how strong it is).
- (Base DLL feature) no Raider ships will spawn, but Raider Land Units can pillage Water Improvements,
    starting 30 Turns after they can start raiding.
- (Base DLL feature) Regents' cognomen Legitimacy contribution to True Heir Legitimacy is halfed (was 100%, now 50%)
- Persian UUs need Melee Range for Rout
- Collateral damage calcalculation is precise again (reverting base game change from v1.0.69678);
- Characters get 1 option to increase a stat point (Rating) even before filling out all 3 strength slots again (reverting base game change from v1.0.70024);
- Event "Other World" now only triggers if the Leader follows a World Religion, and the event uses this religion
- Event Hostile Garrison Expel will still trigger even if your nation gets stronger.
- Event Thunder and Silence Option 1 target City fixed.
- Zealot Leader Enlist Next ability replaced with +2 HP heal per attack against an adjacent Unit (only land-land and water-water)
- AI's "fake" Events can still give Units (was removed in v1.0.72162)
- Cults re-enabled for Competitive Mode (removed in v1.0.72162), most Cult Shrines nerfed: 
  Pagan Statue: +2 Culture (from +4)
  Cavalry Cult: -20% Train Time for Mounted Units, +10% Train Time for Infantry Units (from -50%, +50%)
  Amazon Cult: +1 Order (from +2)
  Martyr Cult: +12 Money, +2 Culture (from +15, +4)
  Dual Cult: +3 Civics (from +5)
  Cult of the Angelic Divine: +2 Culture, +1 Science (from +3, +3)
  Cult of the Mother: +2 Culture (from +4)
  Cult of Isis and Seraphis: +2 Culture, +2 Civics (from +15% Culture, +15% Civics)
  Cult of Mithras: +2 Training, -10% Train time for Melee Units (from +4, -25%)
- Rising Star only gives +1 to all stats (instead of +2),
   as General only gives +1 Happiness per kill (instead of +5),
   as Governor only gives +1 Culture and +2 Growth (instead of +1 Culture per Population and +25% Growth;
- GV nerfed but no longer takes over City producion, and can be assigned at will;
- Slums keep the -25% Unit training time modifiers for Militia and Worker but now also reduce Growth by -10%;
- Estates still give their +1VP but only give +2 Culture and -40% Training, and +5 Family Opinion per Luxury sent to City
   (instead of +1 Culture/-1 Training per Family Opinion Level and +2 Happiness for Luxury sent to City);
- (Base DLL feature) Alternative Character list sorting
- re-enabled Grand Vizier for Competitive Mode (disabled in 74622 update)
- re-enabled 3 tech trade events for Competitive Mode (disabled in 74622 update)
- Cities are immune to Critial Hits again (changed in 74622 update)
- Missions that were changed (in 74622 update) cost Civics again (Slander, Trade, High Synod).


-Siege-related Traits get Bonuses against Forts and Settlements but get reduced Bonus against plain Urban Tiles.
(Siege-related Attack Bonuses: new values (original))
  Besieger*: +25% Urban, +25% Fort (+25% Urban)
  Besieger_all: +10% Urban, +10% Fort (+10% Urban)
  Siege: +25% Settlement, +25% Urban, +50% Fort, 
         +20% Garrison/Stronghold/Citadel (+50% Urban)
  Assault: +25% Settlement, +25% Urban, +25% Fort, 
           +20% Garrison/Stronghold/Citadel (+50% Urban, +50% Fort)
*Besieger is no longer available for Siege Units

When using this together with the Less Scaling Specialist Yields mod, load this mod afterwards, 
otherwise you'd get the Specialist Train Time Discounts from the other mod for the Doctors.

You can contact me on discord, and only there. 
If you try any other way to contact me, my answer could take months.</description>
  <modpicture>FimMod.png</modpicture>
  <author>Fimbulvetr</author>
  <modplatform>Modio</modplatform>
  <modioID>2226901</modioID>
  <modioFileID>0</modioFileID>
  <modversion>0.7.44</modversion>
  <modbuild>1.0.74622</modbuild>
  <homepage>https://forums.civfanatics.com/threads/mod-fims-collection-of-small-mods.678240/</homepage>
  <tags>GameInfo,Event,UI</tags>
  <singlePlayer>true</singlePlayer>
  <multiplayer>true</multiplayer>
  <scenario>false</scenario>
  <scenarioToggle>false</scenarioToggle>
  <blocksMods>false</blocksMods>
  <modDependencies>
    <string>BetterAI-Base</string>
  </modDependencies>
  <modIncompatibilities />
  <modWhitelist />
  <gameContentRequired>NONE</gameContentRequired>
</ModInfo>