<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ModInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <displayName>Older World</displayName>
  <description>A collection of changes, some of them small, some more significant.

The intention behind all changes was not to make a complete overhaul
 but to improve upon what was already there.
Some changes simply revert changes from recent updates to the game.

Requires my Base DLL mod, and incorporates many of my other mods.
Base DLL mod folder name needs to be "BetterAI-Base",  
 you will have to change that manually after first downloading that mod from mod.io
Also requires 0harmony mod for the Harmony dll.

Overview of all changes
*Mission to ask AI to declare War on another player is disabled.  
*Base Discontent generation is +9 for The Good, +14 on The Great, etc.
*Range reduced: Ranged Mounted Units and Tribal Units have a Range of 1,
 Ranged Infantry has Range of 2, Onager and Mangonel have a Range of 2-3.
 Cataphract was nerfed to 8 Str, Circle removed and costs 120 Training. 
*Increased Food consumption: All Units consume more Food, all Population
 consumes 4 Food and nothing else, and no longer changes with Culture Level.
*All Specialists start at Apprentice Level, and Elder Specialists no longer
 give huge yields per Citizen - so no matter how many Elders you train,
 Citizens will always stay useless and just eat your Food.
*Overflow: In Rush Cost calculations, the next turn's Production is accounted for,
 and in exchange no part of it gets added to Stockpile on the next turn.
*Some Wonders were nerfed: Apadana and Lighthouse only affect City instead of the
 whole Nation, and the effects of Pyramids and Ishtar Gate were halfed.
*Only 1 type of Bath per City: Heated for Cold regions, Cold for Hot regions,
 and Warm for Temperate regions. Stats of all Baths are changed. Most significant:
 Heated Baths make Tundra Tiles valid for Urban Improvements.
*There are no Bonus Techs in the Tech Tree.
*Forts are disabled because the AI can still go crazy with them in some situations.
*New Water Unit: the Ferry is an early Ship that can get your Land Units
 across narrow seas, unlocks at Labor Force. Built with Growth, can't be upgraded.
*Early Unlocks: Some Improvements unlock with an earlier Tech for Cities with
 Strong Culture, and some Families have special Unlocks.
*Family Bonuses: Traders, Clerics, Sages had their bonuses revised.
- Clerics: 
  no longer found a Religion, the free tier 4 Tech Bonus (Monasticism) was also removed. 
  Instead they get a Court Soldier, and in their Seat they can rush Projects with Citizens.
  The -50% training time for Disciples applies to all their cities, not just the Seat.
  Clerics unlock in their own Cities:
  -- State Religion's Monasteries with Divination Tech
  -- State Religion's Temples with Metaphysics Tech and Strong Culture in the City
- Traders: 5 Bonuses were removed:
   -10 turns for Hamlet Class Upgrades,
   Road building without cooldown for Family Workers,
   +5 Money from Specialists,
   free Fair in Seat,
   +100% to Nets.
  They were replaced with: 
   5 Orders can be stored for the next turn (tied to the free Early Market Improvement)
   (+15% Money) in Family Seat), 
   +400 Money when Founding a City,
   +2 Culture from Precious Resources,
   +2 Culture from Luxuries sent to City
  Traders unlock in their own Cities:
  -- Ferry Unit (immediately at game start)
  -- Harbor with Navigation Tech and Developing Culture in the City
  -- Market with Polis Tech and Developing Culture in the City
  -- Grocer with Navigation Tech and Strong Culture in the City
- Sages: only Seat gets Archive I, no longer grants a random Tech,
         -20% Upfront Resource Cost for Urban Specilaists
- Patrons keep their +2 Culture from Specialists, and don't get +2 Culture from Precious Resources.
- Statemen keep they Treasury I City founding bonus, and don't get -25% Upfront Cost reduction for Specialists.
- Riders' import Projects don't add the Resource to the map, just enable building the respective Units, Tech requirements like the Units.
- Artisans keep their Ingenuity for Siege Units, only for Ships this is replaced with -25% Resource Cost
***************************************************************************************

Included mods:
*Reduced Range
*More Food Consumption
*Less Scaling Specialist Yields
*Little Family Balance Tweak
*Boat
*No Bonus Techs
*Buy Coastal Tiles
*MinResources
*FimMod

Using all those mods will give you the same result as using this one.

The mod "No Paganism" was not included because some of the new events require Paganism,
 but that mod is compatible and can be used in addition to this mod.


You can contact me on discord, and only there. 
If you try any other way to contact me, my answer could take months.</description>
  <modpicture>OlderWorld3.png</modpicture>
  <author>Fimbulvetr</author>
  <modplatform>Modio</modplatform>
  <modioID>2796259</modioID>
  <modioFileID>0</modioFileID>
  <modversion>0.2.2.23</modversion>
  <modbuild>1.0.73676</modbuild>
  <homepage>https://forums.civfanatics.com/threads/mod-fims-collection-of-small-mods.678240/</homepage>
  <tags>GameInfo,AI,UI</tags>
  <singlePlayer>true</singlePlayer>
  <multiplayer>true</multiplayer>
  <scenario>false</scenario>
  <scenarioToggle>false</scenarioToggle>
  <blocksMods>false</blocksMods>
  <modDependencies>
    <string>0harmony</string>
    <string>BetterAI-Base</string>
  </modDependencies>
  <modIncompatibilities>
    <string>Boat</string>
    <string>BuyCoastal</string>
    <string>FimMod</string>
    <string>Little-Family-Balance-Tweak</string>
    <string>MinResources</string>
    <string>More-Food-Consumption</string>
    <string>No-Bonus-Techs</string>
    <string>Reduced-Range</string>
    <string>Specialist-Yields-Tweak</string>
    <string>Unlimited-Autosaves</string>
    <string>Worker-Extra-Valid</string>
  </modIncompatibilities>
  <modWhitelist />
  <gameContentRequired>NONE</gameContentRequired>
</ModInfo>