<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ModInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <displayName>Minimum Resource Count</displayName>
  <description>Increases the minimum amount of Resource Tiles for every Resource
  
The unmodded game starts resource placements with attempts to place at least 1 of each Resource on the map.
This mod increases this number based on the number of Players (human and AI), and does this special step
 only AFTER normal Resource placement around City Sites has already taken place, and will try to only use 
 unaffiliated Tiles (distance to City Site &gt; 5). 



********************************************************************************************
After City Site Resources are placed, the map generator will start placing Resources on Tiles
 further than 5 Tiles away from City Sites (unaffiliated Tiles). It looks at the number of
 present Resources per type, and if the number is too low, it will try to add more of those.

Resources with high MinLatitude or low MaxLatitude will be modified and can be placed on at least 1/4th or
 1/5th of the map. This affects Olive and Citrus Resources on Arid Plateau and Cold Continent mapscripts.

Luxury Resources: The minimum number of Luxury Resources that the game will aim for
 is 1 + 2/5 * Player number (rounded down) [from 1]
( 1-2 Players: min = 1, 3-4 Players: min = 2, 5-7 Players: min = 3, 8-9 Players: min = 4 )

Non-Luxuries: The minimum number of non-Luxury Resources that the game will aim for
 is 1 + 1/4 * Player number (rounded down) [from 1]
( 1-3 Players: min = 1, 4-7 Players: min = 2, 8-11 Players: min = 3 )

For Luxury Resources that can't get placed on unaffiliated Tiles, City Site tiles will be considered too,
 in an extra step afterwards.
Already placed Luxury resources that were placed in high enough number (at least equal to the number of players,
 or otherwise defined minimum resource count) will be considered for replacement with a Luxury resource that has
 not been placed enough yet. All Tiles that are equally far away from the City Site are possible placement
 locations for the new Luxury resource, not just the Tile of the Resource considered for replacement.
 
Because Resource placement restrictions other than latitude, not all attempts to get these minimum Resource
 numbers will succeed. The process will be part of the logs in %USERPROFILE%\Documents\My Games\OldWorld\Logs\

Secondary feature: Overabundance
During normal placement, which takes place after priority placement for rare Resources,
 the attempts for every Tile to place any overabundant Resources will only take place after
 the attempts to place other Resources has failed.
Since normal placement attempts are RNG-controlled and probabilities are low,
 this feature probably has very little effect.
Overabundance: Number of Resource Tiles greater than 2.5 * Player number (rounded down)
********************************************************************************************


The mod uses Harmony to patch and fully replace
 the AddUnaffiliatedResources method of the DefaultMapScript class,
 as well as WeightedShuffle (the one with the single argument),
 and should therefore be compatible with all mods that don't change those same methods.
It affects all Map Scripts because they all use the Resource distribution methods of DefaultMapScript.

Source code is still included. After some clean-up I will probably upload to GitHub.

Requires 0harmony mod for Harmony DLL</description>
  <modpicture>MinRes.png</modpicture>
  <author>Fimbulvetr</author>
  <modplatform>Modio</modplatform>
  <modioID>2735764</modioID>
  <modioFileID>0</modioFileID>
  <modversion>0.5.1.2</modversion>
  <modbuild>1.0.74622</modbuild>
  <homepage>https://forums.civfanatics.com/threads/mod-fims-collection-of-small-mods.678240/</homepage>
  <tags>GameInfo</tags>
  <singlePlayer>true</singlePlayer>
  <multiplayer>true</multiplayer>
  <scenario>false</scenario>
  <scenarioToggle>false</scenarioToggle>
  <blocksMods>false</blocksMods>
  <modDependencies>
    <string>0harmony</string>
  </modDependencies>
  <modIncompatibilities />
  <modWhitelist />
  <gameContentRequired>NONE</gameContentRequired>
</ModInfo>